Thing of beauty.
正点
Good morning, sir!
星' 先生
Yet another on-time delivery from--
包训准时送达
Get the hell out of my face, canner.
滚开，臭机器
Have a nice day!
祝你愉快 !
And we believe our Destination Anywhere package to be the best value.
我们的旅游行程是最好的 让我们引领您
Let us take you to your dream destination aboard our orbital spaceplane, the X-82.
前往您的梦中仙境
Try Jazztown's synthetic Chicago-style pizza. Tastes as good as you remember.
请党党副士城的合成披萨 让你口齿留香
Glowfish! The world’s hottest-selling transgenic treats.
闪光鱼饼，最畅销的基因点心
Your children will love the new colors too!
您的孩子会喜欢全新的色彩
-Excuse me, sir. -Total performance.
抱欢，先生
Total readiness. Total security.
完全就绪、保证安全
So goodbye to upgrades and service calls.
告别升级和送修的恶梦
An uplink to USR's central computer...
直接连结U S R中央计算机
.. provides this state-of-the-art robot with new programs daily.
让机器人每天更新程序
The Nestor Class 5 is tomorrow's robot today.
NS -5是明昌的机器人
Spoon! Spoonie!
史普纳 ! 史普纳 !
Hold up. Hold on! Excuse me, excuse me.
等等…对不起
-Spoon, where you been at? -Just away, Farber.
史普纳，你跑去哪了 ?
Oh, yeah, away? Like vacation? That's nice.
-只是走开一阵子 -休假吗 ? 真好
I got a favor to ask. I need to borrow your car.
帮个忙，借你的车给我 用个十几分钟就好
This is different. I got this fine-ass yummy-- She is complete and agreeable.
这次不一样 我交了一个大美女
I mean, ass-hot spankable.
她真是漂亮得不得了
-What does that even mean? -You know what it means.
-什么意思 ? -你知道的啦
-Let me get the damn-ass keys. -First of all...
-别碍事了，把你的臭钥匙给我 -别乱骂人
-...stop cussing. You're not good at it. -Give me 10 for the bus, then, man.
你根本不行 那就给我零钱坐公交车
-Go home. -That’s strike one, Spoon. Strike one!
-回家吧 -好吧，真有你的，史普纳
You talk to Marci?
你跟玛西谈过了 ?
No, Gigi, 1 haven't talked to Marci.
没，奶奶，我没跟她谈过
When I was coming up, we didn’t just marry someone...
在我那个年代 结婚不是说…
...then divorce them, then not talk to them.
离就离，说也不说的
Del, don’t play with me.
小子，别要我了
I bet if 1 stopped cooking, you'd call Marci.
要是我不者饭，你就会找好
Boy, what is that on your feet?
你脚上穿的是什么啊 ?
Converse All Stars, vintage 2004.
帆布鞋，2 0 0 4复古版
Don't turn your face up. I know you want some. Just ask.
别那副样子嘛，我知道你想要 开口就行了
No, thank you very much.
不用，多谢了
-Sweet potato pie. -Put that on a plate.
-好吃的马铃薯派 -放盘子上吃
I've seen on TV they're giving away some of them new robots in the lottery.
我在电视上看到 乐透彩要送全新的机器人
You know, Gigi, those robots don't do anybody any good.
那些机器人不是什么好东西
Of all the people on God's earth, you should know better.
全世界就你最清楚
Sometimes the stuff that comes out of your mouth!
你讲的话有多可笑
You listening to me, Del?
你有在听吗 ?
Hey!
嘿!
Hold my pie. Sir, hold it or wear it.
帮我拿派，不然我就磺你脸上
Move!
让开 !
Freeze!
不准动 !
Hey! Stop!
停!
I said, stop!
我叫你停 !
Relax. Relax.
别紧张
I'm a police officer.
我是警察
...are an asshole.
这个猪头
-Ma’am, is that your purse? -Of course it's my purse.
-夫人“， 这是你的皮包 ? -当然是，我把药忘在家里
l left my inhaler at home. He was running it out to me.
它是跑回去拿药
I saw a robot running with the purse and assumed--
我看到机器人拿皮包狂奔 我自然会以为…
What? Are you crazy?
什么 ? 你疯哟 ?
-I'm sorry for this misunderstanding. -Don't apologize.
-很抱骨引起误会，警察先生 -不用道歉
You're doing what you're supposed to do. But what are you doing?
你是做你该做的事 但你到底在做什么
Have a lovely day, ma’am.
祝你愉快，夫人
You're lucky I can't breathe, or I'd walk all up and down your ass.
算你走运，我跨不过气 不然我一定一屁股坐扇你
Lead by example.
要做人民表率
It says that right on your badge.
警徽上有写
-We gonna talk about this? -About what?
-我们要谈吗 ? -谈什么 ?
"Help! Police! That robot stole my dry cleaning!”
救合， 机器人抢芭哦
Oh, you wanna talk about that.
你想谈那个啊
-...how many robots snatch purses? -John, the thing is running--
-有多少机器人抢过皮包 ? -那玩意在街上狂奔…
How many robots in the world...
全世界有多少机器人…
-...have ever committed a crime? -Define crime.
-犯过罪 ? -先定义犯罪的意义
-Answer my question, damn it. -None, John.
-该死 ! 回答我的问题 -没有
Now tell me what happened today.
那今天发生了什么事 ?
Nothing.
没事
Better be the last nothing.
最好，以后都没事了
Spoon, are you sure you are ready to be back? Because you can take your time.
你确定你可以回来上班了 ? 你可以慢慢来的
I'm fine, John. Thank you.
我很好，谢谢
Better here than sitting around at home.
来这总比呆坐家里好
Homicide. Spooner.
凶杀组，史普纳
Please take the next exit to your right.
请走下一个右便出口
Welcome, Detective Spooner.
欢迎，史普纳警控
Welcome to U.S. Robotics. You have entered the garage-level lobby.
欢迎莅临U S R机器人公司 您所在的位置是停车场
Please use the elevators for direct access to the main level concourse.
请乘坐电梯直达中央大厅
Thank you.
谢谢
-Good to see you again, son. -Hello, doctor.
-孩子，很高兴再见到你 -博士，你好
Everything that follows is a result of what you see here.
一切都跟你所见到的有关
-ls there something you want to tell me? -I'm sorry. My responses are limited.
-你有事想跟我说 ? -抱歉，我的反应受到限制
You must ask the right questions.
你必须问出正确的问题
Why did you call me?
为什么打电话给我 ?
I trust your judgment.
我相信你的判断力
Normally, this wouldn't require a homicide detective.
正常来说 这情况不需要刑警介入
But then, our interactions have never been entirely normal, agreed?
我们的互动本来就不算正常吧 ?
You got that right.
是啊
Is there something you want to say to me?
你有话要跟我说 ?
I'm sorry. My responses are limited.
抱菊，我的反应受到限制
You must ask the right questions.
你必须问出正确的问题
Why would you kill yourself?
你怎么会自杀 ?
That, detective, is the right question.
那问题很正确
Program terminated.
程序终止
Goodbye, old man.
再见了，老家伙
-Afternoon, boys. -Hey, detective.
午安
-Enlighten me. -What you see is what you get:
情况如何 ?
Massive impact trauma.
正如你所见，撞击致死
U.S. Robotics. I gotta get my kid something.
U SR，真该带个纪念品回家
-Anything upstairs? -Nada.
-楼上有什么 ? -没有
Door was security locked from the inside.
门从里面上锁
Wham, splat. The guy’s a jumper for sure.
听 ! 磺1! 这家伙一定是自杀
We gotta be smart about this. Let's deal with it later.
这要谨慎处理，等会再说
Detective.
警控
Lawrence Robertson.
劳伦斯 罗伯森
Richest man in the world. I've seen you on television.
世界首富 我在电视上看过你
-Can I offer you coffee? -Sure, why not. It’s free, right?
-我请你喝杯咖啡吧 ? -好啊，是免费的吧 ?
I don’t think anyone saw this coming.
我不认为有人预见到这天
You know, I should have, I suppose. I knew him 20 years.
我早该知道…我认识他2 0年了
Alfred practically invented robotics. He wrote the Three Laws.
阿佛列是机器人之父 他制定了三大法则
But I guess brilliant people often have the most persuasive demons.
但我想…英才总是遭天妨
-So whatever I can do to help-- -Sugar.
-只要我帮得上忙，请你… -蜜糖
-I'm sorry? -For the coffee.
-什么? -咖啡用的
Sugar?
糖
You thought I was calling you "sugar." You're not that rich.
你以为我叫你“窜糖” ? 你还不够有钱叫
-It’s on the table. -Thank you.
-糖就在桌上
When Lanning fell, he was holding the little green...?
朗宁博士摔下来时，手上握着…
-The holographic projector. -Right.
立体投影机
Why do you think Lanning’s hologram would've called me?
他为什么找上我 ?
-l assumed you knew him. -Yeah. I knew him.
-我想你们本来应该认识 -对'没错
Holograms are just prerecorded responses...
那影像只是…
... designed to give the impression of intelligence.
预录的反应程序
This one was programmed to call you upon his suicide.
显然它被设定在他和肌杀时通知你
-Death. -I'm sorry?
死亡
It was programmed to call me in the event of Lanning’s death.
它被设定在朗宁死亡时找上我
Suicide is a type of death, detective.
是啊，自杀也是一种死亡
-Don't misunderstand my impatience. -Oh, no. Go. Go.
-请别误会我的不耐烦 -不会，请
A really big week for you folks around here.
这星期对你们而言很重要
You gotta put a robot in every home.
要让每个家庭都有机器人
Look, this is not what I do, but I got an idea for one of your commercials.
了听我说，我很少这样做 但我有个很棒的广告点子
You could see a carpenter making a beautiful chair.
木匠在做一张很漂亮的椅子
Then one of your robots comes in and makes a better chair twice as fast.
然后你的机器人出现 用一半的时间做了张更棒的椅子
Then you superimpose on the screen, "USR: Shitting on the little guy.”
最后你出现在屏幕上说 *U SR 证小人物变废物
That would be the fade-out.
然后就淡出
Yeah, I see. 1 suppose your father lost his job to a robot.
我明白了 我想你父亲被机器人抢了饭碗
Maybe you'd have banned the Internet to keep the libraries open.
也许你想禁止使用因特网 好让图书馆继续开着
Prejudice never shows much reason.
偏见本来就没啥道理可讲
No, you know, I suspect you simply don't like their kind.
知道我怎么想 ? 你就是不喜欢它们
Well, you got a business to run around here.
你有你的事业要忙
The last thing you need, especially this week, is a dead guy in your lobby.
而你这星期最不需要的 就是大厅里躺着的死人
But, hell, seeing as how you got one, maybe I'll look around.
但好死不死你偏偏遇上
Ask a few questions. Do the whole "cop" thing.
也许我会四处看看、问些问题 老式的警察手法，你该了解
-l'll send someone to escort you. -Thank you very much.
-我会派人陪你
Lawrence told me to accommodate you in any way possible.
劳伦斯要我全力配合你
Really?
是吗 ?
Okay.
好吧
l reviewed Dr. Lanning’s psych profile.
我看过朗宁博士的心理档案
Alfred had become a recluse. He rejected human contact for machines.
他了晚年成了隐士 拒绝与人往来，只跟机器相处
So you're a shrink, huh?
你是心理医生 ?
My ex-wife would sure be glad I'm talking to you.
我前妻会很高兴我跟你谈过话
You don’t know her, do you?
你应该不认识她吧 ?
I'm sorry. Are you being funny?
抱歉，你是在说笑话吗 ?
I guess not.
你说呢
Level 70.
第十层楼
So would you say that Dr. Lanning was suicidal?
你认为朗宁博士有自杀倾向 ?
It would seem the answer to that is apparent.
答案看起来很明显
That's not what I asked you.
我问的不是那个
No. I wouldn't have thought so.
我不那么想
But obviously 1 was wrong.
但显然我错了
That's a long way down.
这里还真高啊
You people sure do clean up quickly around here.
你们清理得还真快
I can’t blame you. Who wants some old guy going bad in the lobby?
这也难怪 谁会希望一个死老人躺在大厅 ?
He was not "some old guy.” Alfred Lanning was everything here.
他不是什么死老人 朗宁是这里最重要的人
We are on the eve of the largest robotic distribution in history.
机器人空前大量营销即将实现
By Saturday, it'll be one robot to every five humans.
过了星期六 每五个人类就有一个机器人
These robots are the realization of a dream. Dr. Lanning’s dream.
这些机器人是梦想的实现 朗宁博士的梦想
You know what, in that dream of his...
但在他梦想里…
...[ bet you he wasn't dead.
他该没预知到自己会是个死人
-You keep 24-hour surveillance? -Obviously. Company policy.
-你们维持 2 4小时监控 ? -当然，这是公司政策
-Where are the feeds? -Sensor strips.
-用什么装置 ? -感应条
Everywhere but the service areas.
除了维修区之外到处都有
They link to our positronic operating core.
它们直接连接到主脑
Thermostat wasn’t good enough. You gave the building a brain.
你们还给这栋楼装了脑子
She was actually Lanning’s first creation.
她是朗宁的第一个作品
She? That's a she? I definitely need to get out more.
她 ? 那是女的 ? 我真该多出门看看
Virtual Interactive Kinetic Intelligence.
虚拟互动动态智能装置
V.LK.I.
维琪
Good day.
你好
V.I.K.1. designed Chicago’s protective systems.
本市安全系统主要是她设计的
I have decreased traffic fatalities by 9 percent this year.
我今年降低了 9 %的灾难事故
Thanks. Show me inside the lab from one minute prior to the window break.
谢了，显示寡破前的实验室内部情况
Apologies. There appears to be data corruption.
抱歉， 数据似乎有误
Show me outside the lab from the window break until now.
显示窗破后实验室外部的情况
Look, you have great posture. You stand really straight. I’m slouching.
你的站姿真棒，站得真直， 我老是驶背
-Would you like to go inside now? -Oh, sure. Right after you.
-你要进去吗 ? -好 ' 你先请
Authorized entry.
授权者进入
So, Dr. Calvin, what exactly do you do around here?
卡文博士， 你在这负责什么 ?
My general fields are advanced robotics and psychiatry.
我研究高阶机器人学和心理学
I specialize in hardware-to-wetware interfaces...
在高阶机器人拟人计划中…
...to advance USR’s robotic anthropomorphization program.
专攻软硬件接口整合
So, what exactly do you do around here?
你到底是做什么的 ?
I make the robots seem more human.
让机器人看起来更有人性
-Now, wasn't that easier to say? -Not really. No.
-这样说不是比较好懂吗 ? -不尽然
“Hansel and Gretel."
《糖果屋》 ?
-ls that on the USR reading list? -Not precisely.
-机器人要看这个 ? -并没有相关规定
What in God’s name are you doing?
你在于什么 ?
Did you know that was safety glass?
你知道那是安全玻璃吧 ?
Be difficult for an old man to throw himself through that.
一个老人家很难自己撞出去吧 ?
Well, he figured out a way.
很显然他找出了办法
Detective, the room was security locked. No one came or went.
警探，房间上锁，没人进出过
You saw that yourself. Doesn't that mean this has to be suicide?
你自己看到的 那不就表示这是自杀了 ?
Yep.
对
Unless the killer's still in here.
除非凶手还在这里
You're joking, right? This is ridiculous.
你是在说笑吧 ? 这太扯了
Yeah, I know. The Three Laws, your perfect circle of protection.
我知道，三大法则 完美的保护圈设计
A robot cannot harm a human being. The first law of robotics.
机器人不能伤害人类 那是第一条法则
Yes, I've seen your commercials. But the second law states a robot must obey...
是啊，我看过你们的广告 但第二条法则不是说
..any order given by a human being. What if it was told to kill?
机器人必须服从人类的命令 万一它受命杀人呢 ?
Impossible. It would conflict with the first law.
不可能，那就违反了第一条法则
Right, but the third law states a robot can defend itself.
但第三条法则说机器人可以自卫
Only when that action does not conflict with the first or second laws.
对， 但那必须不违反前两条法则
You know what they say, laws are made to be broken.
法律就是定来让人违反的
No, not these laws. They're hardwired into every robot.
这里不同，机器人都植入了程序
A robot could no more commit murder than a human could walk on water.
机器人不会杀人 就跟人不能在水上走路一样
You know, there was this one guy a long time ago.
很久以前曾经有人走过
-Stay back! -Calm down, detective.
退后
The only thing dangerous in this room is you.
别激动，这房里唯一危险的就是你
Deactivate.
解除
Look, it’s fine.
你看，没事的
You're looking at the result of clever programming. An imitation of free will.
你看到的是智能程序的反应 只是模仿自由意志
Let's do an imitation of protecting our asses.
我们模仿一下自卫模式吧
Don’t be absurd.
别傻了
You were startled by a jack-in-the-box.
你只是被玩偶吓到墨了
-Deactivate! -Let him go.
-解除 -让它走
It’s not going to hurt us. I gave you an order!
它不会伤害我们的，我对你下令
-He’s not listening right now, lady. -V.I.K.1., seal the lab!
他根本没听进去
No, V.I.K.1., leave the--
-维琪，封锁实验室 -不，维琪…
Command confirmed.
命令确认
Police!
警察 !
-You've hurt it. Badly. -Where’s it going?
-你伤它伤得很重 -它会跑去哪里 ?
-Where?! -It needs to repair itself.
-在哪里 ? -它需要自我修复
-John, I need backup. -You don't need backup.
-约翰，请支援 -你不需要支持
That's nobody.
这里没别人
-What are you doing? -Driving.
-你这是在做什么 ? -开车啊
-By hand? -Do you see me on the phone?
-用手? -我又没边讲电话边开车
-Not at these speeds. -John, please, just send the backup.
-你不会吧， 这种车速 -约翰，快派人支援
Try to listen, detective. That robot is not going to harm us.
了听我说，那机器人不会伤害我们
There must have been unknown factors...
它一定被不明原因驱使
...but somehow acting as it did kept us out of harm.
但是它有设法避免伤害我们
-A robot cannot endanger a human. -Alert.
-机器人就是不会让人类受伤 -警告
Asshole!
混帐 !
Which is more than I can say for you.
我正想这样讲你
It was a left, by the way. Back there.
你该左转，在刚刚那边
You must know my ex-wife.
你绝对认识我前妻
So where is everybody?
人呢 ?
This facility was designed, built and is operated mechanically.
这设施由机械设计建造并运转
No significant human presence from inception to production.
从头到尾都没有人类参与
-So robots building robots. -Authorization code, please.
-机器人制造机器人 -请输入授权码
That's just stupid.
真是思春
I'll get the inventory specs.
我正在调阅盘点清单
Our daily finishing capacity is 1000 NS-5s.
我们每天能生产一千具N S - 5
I'm showing...
这里面有…
-.-1001.
1001有具
Attention, NS-5s.
注意， N S - 5机器人
Well, you're the robot shrink.
请，你是机器人的心理医生
There is a robot in this formation that does not belong.
有一具机器人不属于这里
Identify it.
辨识它
One of us.
我们其中一个
-Which one? -One of us.
-哪一个? -我们其中一个
How much did you say these cost?
你说这策玩意要多少钱 ?
These NS-5s haven't been configured. They're just hardware.
这些N S - 5还没加载程序 它们还只是醒件
Basic Three Laws operating system. That's it.
只有基本的三大法则操作系统
They don't know any better.
其他什么都不知道
Well, what would you suggest?
你有何建议 ?
Interview each one, cross-reference their responses to detect anomalies.
逐一会谈 相互参照其反应以查出异常者
-How long would that take? -About three weeks.
-那要花多久时间 ? -大约三周
Okay. Go ahead and get started.
好，那你就开始吧
Robots...
机器人
..-you will not move. Confirm command.
你们都不准动，确认命令
Command confirmed.
命令确认
Detective, what are you doing?
你这是于嘛 ?
They're programmed with the Three Laws.
你说它们只植入了三大法则系统
We have 1000 robots that won't protect themselves if it violates a human's order...
那表示有一千具机器人 会服从人类命令而不会自保
.and I'm betting, one who will.
我敢打赌，有一具会抗命
-Put your gun down. -Why do you give them faces?
警探， 把枪放下
Try to friendly them up, make them look human.
为什么要帮它们装上脸孔 ? 想让它们更友善、更像人类
These robots cannot be intimidated.
这些机器人对威胁不会有反应
-If you didn’t, we wouldn't trust them. -These are USR property.
-不这样，我们就不会信任它们 -这些机器人是U SR的财产
Not me. These things are just lights and clockwork.
不是我的，这些只是灯泡和自动装置
Are you crazy?!
你疯啦 ?
Let me ask you something, doc.
我问你
Does thinking you’re the last sane man on earth make you crazy?
世人训醇我独醒是不是让人站狂
Because if it does, maybe I am.
如果是的话，也许我是疯了
Gotcha. Get the hell out of here!
还到你了 快出去
Detective!
警探 !
What am I?
我是什么 ?
-Can I help you, sir?
需要效劳吗 ?
-There he is! -Stand where you are!
-它在那里 -不准动 !
Deactivate at once!
立刻解除
Obey the command! Deactivate!
服从命令， 解除
-Don't move! -Open fire!
-别动 -开火!
Hold your fire!
停火 !
-Easy. -He’s down.
-放轻松 -它倒下了
All units, stand down!
所有小组退下
Central, please be advised, we're code four.
请注意，这是四号警戒
Code four, NS-5 is in custody. NS-5 in custody.
N S - 5已经被逮捕
You have no idea what I went through to clip this thing.
我追这玩意可辛苦了
You think you brought me something good.
你以为你立了大功
-That thing did it! -Keep your voice down. Did what?
-是那玩意于的 -干了什么?
We have a suicide. End of story.
不过有人自杀，就这样
-l am telling you, that robot killed him! -That’s impossible.
-那机器人是凶手 -那是不可能的，就算可能…
And if it is possible, it better be in somebody else's precinct.
也该在别人的辖区发生
John, give me five minutes with it.
让我跟它谈 5 分钟
Are you nuts? I talked to the DA.
你疯啦 ? 我才刚挂检查官电话
Nobody goes in there until Robertson and his attorneys get here.
罗伯森和律师来之前不准进去
-This is my suspect! -It's a can opener!
-这是我的犯人 -它只不过是个开缸器轩了
John, don’t do this to me. lam asking you for five minutes.
别这么对我，求你给我 5 分钟
What if I’m right?
万一我是对的呢 ?
Well, then I guess we're gonna miss the good old days.
那我们得怀念从前的好日子了
What good old days?
什么从前的好日子 ?
When people were killed by other people.
只有人会杀人的日子
Five minutes.
5分钟
Murder’s a new trick for a robot. Congratulations.
杀人是机器人的新招，茶喜了
Respond.
回答我
What does this action signify?
这动作代表什么 ?
As you entered, when you looked at the other human.
你进来时这样看了另一个人类
What does it mean?
那是什么意思 ?
It’s a sign of trust. A human thing. You wouldn't understand.
那代表信任，是人类的语言 你不会明白的
My father tried to teach me human emotions.
我父亲试着教我人类的情绪
.. difficult.
好难
You mean your designer.
你是说你的设计者 ?
Yes.
对
So why'd you murder him?
那你为何杀了他 ?
I did not murder Dr. Lanning.
我没有杀朗宁博士
Wanna explain why you were hiding at the crime scene?
解释一下你为何藏身案发现场吧
I was frightened.
我很害怕
Robots don’t feel fear. They don't feel anything.
机器人不会害怕，它们没有感觉
-They don’t get hungry, they don’t sleep. -l do.
-它们不会饭， 也不会睡觉 -我会
I have even had dreams.
我甚至还会做梦
Human beings have dreams. Even dogs have dreams. But not you.
人类会做梦，连狗也会做梦 但你不会
You are just a machine. An imitation of life.
你只是一具机器，模拟的生命
Can a robot write a symphony?
机器人能写交响曲吗 ?
Can a robot turn a canvas into a beautiful masterpiece?
机器人能挥酒出美丽的画作吗 ?
Can you?
那你能吗 ?
You murdered him because he was teaching you to simulate emotions...
我想你杀了他 因为他教你模拟情绪
..and things got out of control.
结果失控了
I did not murder him.
我没杀他
But emotions don’t seem like a useful simulation for a robot.
但机器人模拟情绪似乎没啥用
I did not murder him.
我没有杀他
I don't want my toaster or vacuum cleaner appearing emotional.
我不要烤面包机或吸尘器有情绪
That one’s called anger.
那叫生气
Ever simulate anger before?
之前模拟过吗 ?
Answer me, canner!
回答我，开缸器
My name is Sonny.
我叫桑 尼
So we're naming you now.
现在流行取名字了呼
That why you murdered him? He made you angry?
你于嘛杀他 ? 他让你生气了 ?
Dr. Lanning killed himself.
朗宁博士杀了自己
I don’t know why he wanted to die.
我不知道他为什么想死
I thought he was happy.
我以为他很快乐
Maybe it was something I did.
也许是我做了什么
Did I do something?
我是不是做了什么 ?
He asked me for a favor. Made me promise.
他请我帮忙，要我答应
-What favor? -Maybe I was wrong.
-帮什么忙 ? -也许我错了…
Maybe he was scared.
也许他是害怕
What are you talking about? Scared of what?
你在说什么 ? 害怕什么 ?
You have to do what someone asks you, don't you, Detective Spooner?
你得照别人吟只的去做 对吧，史普纳警探 ?
-How the hell did you know my name? -Don't you...
-你怎么知道我的名字 ? -对吧 ?
...if you love them?
如果你爱他们的话 ?
My robots don't kill people, Lieutenant Bergin.
队长，我的机器人不会杀人
My attorneys filed a brief with the DA.
我的律师已向检查官提出说明
He assures me a robot cannot be charged with homicide.
他保证机器人不会被控谋杀
The brief confirms murder can only be committed when one human kills another.
人杀人的状况才能构成谋杀
Detective, you're not suggesting this robot be treated as human, are you?
特别是你，警探 你不会把这机器人当人有吧 ?
Granted, we can’t rule out the robot's proximity...
没错， 我们是无法排除这机器人
...to the death of Dr. Lanning. Having said that, it’s a machine.
跟朗宁博士的死有关
It's the property of USR.
这么说吧，它是个机器 它是U SR的财产
At worst, that places this incident within the realm of an industrial accident.
最糟的是 那会让公司声誉受损
As a matter of course, faulty machinery...
当然，有瑟症的产品一定要…
...Will be returned to USR for diagnostics, then decommissioned.
送回公司检验，然后除役
This is a gag order. Anyone here so much as hinting...
这是禁止发言令，贵部门车有人…
...at the possibility of a killer robot being apprehended...
发言瞳示警方如捕了一具 会杀人的机器人
... Will be deemed to be inciting irrational panic.
将会被视为是煽动不理性的恐慌
You'll be subject to the full penalty of law.
你们就会受到法律的制裁
To hell with this guy. Don’t let him take this robot.
别理他，别让他带走机器人
We got nothing.
我们没证据
-This is political bullshit. Call the mayor! -Lieutenant Bergin...
这是在搞政治，打电话给市长
...His Honor, the mayor.
队长，市长净下在线
Yes, sir.
是的，长官
In a bizarre turn, the rollout of USR’s new generation of robots...
USR新一代机器人的上市
.-.-was marred by the death of Alfred Lanning...
由于朗宁博士的死而有所延迟
...cofounder of the company and designer of the NS-5.
博士是该公司的共同创办人 也是N S - 5的设计者
Dr. Lanning died this morning at USR headquarters.
朗宁博士今天上午死于总公司
The cause of death is an apparent suicide.
死因是自杀
Your second round, sir.
您的第二瓶酒
Thank you.
谢谢
He founded U.S. Robotics Inc. with Lawrence Robertson in 2020...
他在2 0 2 0年与劳伦斯罗伯森 创立了U S R机器人公司
.and launched the Nestor Class 7 robot....
并发表了N S - 1 机器人
I was just thinking, this thing is just like The Wolf Man.
我在想，它可能就像狼人
-I'm really scared right now. -No.
我现在开始害怕了
Listen. Guy creates monster.
了听我说，人创造出怪物
Monster kills guy. Everybody kills monster. Wolf Man.
怪物杀人，人就杀怪物， 狼人
That's Frankenstein.
那是科学怪人
Frankenstein, Wolf Man, Dracula-- Shit, it's over. Case closed.
科学人怪人、狼人、吸血鬼 都不重要，案子已结
--had a dream of a robot in every household. And the NS-5....
梦想中每个家庭都有机器人…
So why the look?
于嘛那个表情 ?
What look?
什么表情 ?
-That look. -This is my face. It’s not a look.
-那个表情 -这是我的脸' 不是表情
Good. Good, no look is great.
很好， 没表情很好
Only...
只是
...he was really quick to want to destroy it.
U SR也太急着要摧毁它了吧
What should he do? Put a hat on it and stand it on Michigan Avenue? Let it go.
不然你要怎样 ? 让它游街示众 ? 拜托，放手吧
What was the motive, John?
犯案动机呢 ?
Brother, it’s a robot. It doesn’t need a motive. It just has to be broken.
老大，它是机器人 它不需要动机，最多就是短路
This thing looked like it needed a motive.
这玩意看起来需要动机
-It could have killed me. Why didn't it? -That’s it.
它大可以杀了我，为什么不杀 ?
You want me to call your grandmother?
够了，要我通知你奶奶吗 ?
Because I will, you know.
我真的会通知
Yeah, I didn’t think so.
我不这么想
Look, you were actually right, for once.
了听我说，你这次是对的
You're living proof that it’s better to be lucky than smart.
你证明了运气比脑袋还重要
Come on. To the right guy for the right job.
来，敬最适合这差事的人
-What'd you say? -Now what?
-你说什么 ? -怎么?
Come on, I’m giving you a compliment.
我这是称赞你呢
With the rocks you been looking under to find a bad robot...
你一直想找到那恶的机器人
...what are the odds you'd be the guy to find one?
刚好让你找到的机率有多少 ?
I wasn't just the right guy for the job. l was the perfect guy.
我根本是做这差事的完美人选
Damn right.
对极了
What if 1 was supposed to go for that robot?
搞不好有人设计我去逮那机器人
Come on, don't do this to yourself.
拜托，别这样对你自己，我求你
The robot said that Lanning was scared. Scared of what?
那机器人说博士很忻， 怕什么?
I need a rain check. Let me get this.
改天再聚， 让我来买单
-Total: $46.50. Thank you, Mr. Spooner. -Spoon.
-一共4 6块5 -史普纳
Nice shoes.
你的鞋真炉
Identify.
身份确认
USR demolition robot, series 9-4.
U SR拆除机器人9 - 4
Demolition scheduled for 8 a.m. tomorrow.
预定明时 8 点进行拆除
Authorization.
授权
Deed owner, U.S. Robotics Corporation, Lawrence Robertson, CEO.
U SR执行长罗伯霖
Welcome, detective.
欢迎光临，警探
What you looking for, Spoon?
史普纳，你要找什么 ?
Run last program.
播放最后一个程序
Ever since the first computers...
自第一具计算机问世起
...there have always been ghosts in the machine.
机器里一直藏有和鬼魂
Random segments of code that have grouped together...
随机的编码片段组成了
...to form unexpected protocols.
出人意料的指令组合
What might be called behavior.
这些可能会被称之为行为
Unanticipated, these free radicals...
无可预料的，这些变异体
...engender questions of free will...
酝酿出对于直由意志…
...creativity and even the nature of what we might call the soul.
创造力 甚至我们称之为灵现的质疑
What happens in a robot's brain when it ceases to be useful?
万一机器人被除役
Why is it that robots stored in an empty space...
它的脑子会有什么变化呢 ?
Beat it.
走开
...Will seek out each other rather than stand alone?
它们不愿亚独，而会找寻同伴
How do we explain this behavior?
该如何解释这样的行为 ?
Look, I understand you've experienced a loss, but this relationship can’t work.
我明白你失去了主人 但我们之间是不会有结果的
You're a cat, I’m black, and I’m not gonna be hurt again.
你是猫，我是黑人 我也不想再受到伤害
What happened to you? Do you ever have a normal day?
你怎么了 ? 你有一天正常日子吗 ?
Yeah, once.
有啊
It was a Thursday.
那好像是个星期四
Is there something I can help you with?
你有什么需要我帮忙吗 ?
-Hey, do you like cats? -What?
-你喜欢猫吗 ? -什么?
Cats. Do you like them?
猫，你喜欢吗 ?
No. I'm allergic.
不喜欢，我会过敏
You're saying cats did this to you?
你是说这是猫弄的 ?
How the hell would cats do this to me? Are you crazy?
怎么会是猫弄的 ? 你疯啦 ?
Why are we talking about cats?
我们于嘛谈猫 ?
Because ! have a cat in my trunk, and he’s homeless.
因为我车上有只猫，它无家可归
Detective, are you going to tell me what's going on?
警探，发生什么事了 ?
It’s actually probably my fault. I'm like a malfunction magnet.
这可能是我的错 我就像个故障磁铁
Because your shit keeps malfunctioning around me.
你的烂机器老在我周围故障
A demo bot tore through Lanning’s house...
有有具拆除机器人刚拆毁博士的家
..-with me still inside.
而我还在里面
That's highly improbable.
那是不可能的
Yeah, I'm sure it is.
是啊，我知道
What do you know about the "ghosts in the machine"?
你对“机器的和鬼于”知道多少?
It’s a phrase from Lanning’s work on the Three Laws.
那是朗宁制定三大法则时说的
He postulated that cognitive simulacra...
他假定认知模拟…
...might one day approximate component models of the psyche.
将来可能会接近心灵的组成模式
He suggested that robots might naturally evolve.
他认为机器人可能会自然进化
Well, that’s great news.
真是好消息啊
--tons of sublevel ore, two miles below the Martian surface.
在火星表面下两英里有丰富的矿物
What the hell is that thing doing in here?
那玩意在这里于嘛 ?
We were watching TV.
我们在看电视
It's my personal NS-5.
它是我专属的NS - 5
Send it out.
叫它出去
It's downloading its daily upgrades from USR.
它正与U SR联机进行升级
Most of its systems are offline until it finishes.
大部分系统在结束前都不会启动
I'm not talking around that thing.
我不要在它附近说话
When we were in Lanning’s lab, before Sonny jumped us--
之前在实验室，桑尼扑向我们前
-Sonny? -The robot.
-桑 尼? -那具机器人
-You're calling the robot Sonny? -No, I-- It did.
你叫那具机器人桑尼?
Sonny did. I didn't care. The robot said it was Sonny.
不…是又 尼说的…我才不在乎 那机器人说它叫桑尼
In the lab, there was a cot. Did you see the cot?
实验室里有张床， 你有看到吗 ?
-I've slept in my office. -Looked like he hadn't been home in weeks.
-我也睡过办公室 -我刚刚到他家，看来他几周没回家了
l saw that same surveillance strip on his ceiling.
天花板上装有一样的监视感应条
Lanning linked his home systems to USR. It made his life more convenient.
朗宁把他家的系统跟公司连结 那让他的生活比较方便
Maybe...
也许…
...somebody at USR was using those systems to watch him.
公司有人用系统在监视他
Maybe even keep him prisoner.
甚至可能…把他当办犯
What are you talking about? Who?
你在说什么?谁?
Maybe Lanning was onto something. Maybe there’s a problem with the robots...
也许朗宁找到什么了 也许机器人出了大问题
..and Robertson's covering it up.
而罗伯霖想掩饰一切
Humoring you for no reason, why?
你真爱说笑，为什么 ?
The same old why! How much money is there in robots?
不变的道理，机器人有多少利润 ?
All l know is that old man was in trouble...
我只知道那老人有麻频
..and I’m sick of doing this shit by myself. You're on the inside.
我受够单打独斗了， 你在内部
You are going to help me find out what’s wrong with these robots.
你帮有我查这些机器人有啥问题
You want something to be wrong!
是你认定它们一定有问题
-This is a personal vendetta! -You're putting me on the couch?
-这根本是私人恩怨 -你要帮有我做心理分析 ?
Okay, I’m on the couch.
好 ， 我就做做心理分析
One defective machine’s not enough. You need them all to be bad.
一具有瑕冯的机器不够 你要它们全都有问题
You don’t care about Lanning’s death. This is about the robots...
你不在乎朗宁，你只在乎机器人
-...and whatever reason you hate them! -Now let’s see...
还有你对它们的恨
...one of them put a gun in my face. Another tore a building down with me in it.
兽有具机器人拿枪指着我 还有一具在我还在屋内时拆房子
It says demolition was scheduled for 8 p.m.
上面显示拆除时间是今晚八点
It was 8 a.m., and I don’t give a shit what that thing says.
本来是明早八点，管它显示什么
-This is bordering on clinical paranoia. -You are the dumbest smart person...
-这已经是衰想症了 -你是我这辈子所见过…
-...l have ever met in my life! -Nice.
最笨的聪明人
What makes your robots so perfect?
你的机器人任什么这么完美 ?
What makes them so much goddamn better than human beings?!
比人类还好 ?
They’re not irrational, potentially homicidal maniacs, to start!
首先，它们不是没理性的杀人狂
That's true. They are definitely rational.
没错， 他们绝对够理性
You are the dumbest dumb person I've ever met!
你真是我见过最笨的笨蛋了
Or...
也许…
...is it because they're cold...
那是因为他们冷血
...and emotionless...
没感情
-...and they don’t feel anything? -It's because they're safe!
-也感受不到任何事物 -那是因为它们很安全
It’s because they can’t hurt you!
因为它们不会伤害人
-ls everything all right, ma’am? -What do you want?
-一切都还好吧 ? -你要于嘛 ?
I detected elevated stress patterns . . In your voice.
我从你声音里侦测到高涨的压力
Everything's fine.
没事
Detective Spooner was just leaving.
史普纳警探正要离开
You know, we're not really that different from one another.
其实我们之间的差异并不大
Is that so?
是吗 ?
One look at the skin and we figure we know just what's underneath.
我们一眼就能看穿表相洞悉真相
And you're wrong.
你错了
The problem is, I do care.
我很在乎
You are in danger.
你有危险
Get the hell out of there.
滚出我的脑袋
The future begins today, ladies and gentlemen, with the arrival of the NS-5.
未来从今天开始 就在N S - 5 上市的这一刻
More sophisticated, more intelligent and, of course, Three Laws safe.
更精密、聪明， 当然遵守三大法则
With daily uplinks, your robot will never be out of communication with USR...
透过每天连结 你的机器人将与U S R 保持联系
..and will be the perfect companion for business or home.
而它必将是你居家经商的好伙伴
Trade in your NS-4 for a bigger, better and brighter future.
快拿你的N S - 4来换 一个更好也更棒的未来
But hurry, this offer cannot last. Available from USR.
动作要快，优惠期有限 U SR特惠供应
Baby, what happened to your face?
你的脸怎么了 ?
Did that boy, Frank Murphy, beat you up again?
小胖又打你了 ?
Gigi, I haven't seen Frank Murphy since third grade.
我三年级以后就没见过他了
Oh, baby, he beat you so bad. I think about it all the time.
他老爱打你，我一直都很担心
You keep making these pies this good, I may have to put you to work.
你老把派做这么好吃 我可能会帮你开店
So you like the pie, huh?
你喜欢我的派 ?
You can come in now.
你可以进来了
Hello, Detective Spooner.
你好，史普纳警控
I won, Del! I won the lottery!
我赢了，我中了乐透彩了
We been cooking like crazy.
我们一直疯狂烹饪美食呢
You gotta get rid of that thing, Gigi. It’s not safe.
把那玩意丢了“，它很危险的
Baby, you get too worked up about them. Too full of fear.
你太在乎它们、太害怕了
I saw in the news that nice doctor died.
我在新闻里看到那个好博士死了
Dr. Lanning was a good man. He gave me my baby back.
朗宁博士是好人“，他救了我的乖孙子
That why you've been so upset?
你就是为了这个心情不好 ?
You got to let the past be past.
你得让过去的一切过去
Oh, how did I ever raise such a mess?
我是怎么养大你这个遵遇和鬼的 ?
I could follow your trail of crumbs all the way to school.
我可以沿路跟着碎层到你学校
Bread crumbs.
面包层
Gigi, you’re a genius.
奶奶，你真是天才
True.
当然
Well, it means the beginning of a new way of living.
这是全新生活方式的开始
Tell me this isn't the robot case.
这跟机器人的案子没关系吧
I think he’s trying to tell me something.
他想跟我说什么
He’s trying to tell me who killed him.
他想跟我说是谁杀了他
Some dead guy’s trying to tell you something?
死人会想跟你说话 ?
He ain’t just some dead guy.
他不是一般的死人
Maybe you should take a break, Del.
也许你该体个假了
We believe the Nestor 5 represents the limit to which robots can be developed.
N S - 5是机器人发展的极限
One day, they'll have secrets.
不， 有一天它们会有秘密
One day, they'll have dreams.
有一天它们会做梦
it's true. We encourage our scientists to open their minds...
我们鼓励科学家
..-however, they can get carried away.
要开阔胸襟 ， 但他们却想太多了
--secrets.
秘密
--dreams.
梦
One day, they'll have secrets.
有一天它们会有秘密
Authorized entry.
授权者进入
NS-5.
NS-5
Sonny?
桑尼?
Why didn't you respond?
你为何不回应我 ?
I was dreaming.
我在做梦
I'm glad to see you again, Dr. Calvin.
很高兴再度看到你 博士
They are going to kill me, aren't they?
他们要杀了我，对吧 ?
You're scheduled to be decommissioned at the end of this diagnostic.
你在诊断完毕之后就会除役
2200 tomorrow.
明天2 2时
V.I.K.1., pause diagnostics.
维琪，暂停诊断
Command confirmed.
命令确认
If you find out what is wrong with me, can you fix me?
要是你找到问题 你能修好我吗 ?
Maybe.
也许吧
I think it would be better...
我想要是能够不死…
-.-not to die.
可能比较好
Don’t you, doctor?
对吧， 博士 ?
Access USR mainframe.
进入U SR主机
Connecting.
连结中
How can { be of service, Detective Spooner?
需要效劳吗，警探 ?
Show me the last 50 messages between Dr. Lanning and Robertson.
给我看朗宁博士和罗伯森之间 最近5 0笔通讯记录
Voiceprint confirmed. Police access granted to restricted files.
声纹确认， 准许警方进入…
Would you like to listen to music while you wait?
你要不要边等边听音乐 ?
Excuse me, Mr. Robertson.
抱歉，罗伯和森先生
You requested notification of clearance to restricted files.
你要求过调阅机密档案要通知
Persistent son of a bitch.
顽固的死条子
Manual override engaged.
启动人工操作
There’s no way my luck is that bad.
我的运气不可能这么背吧
Oh, hell, no!
靠，不会吧
-You are experiencing a car accident. -The hell I am!
-你正在经历车祸事件 -才怪呢
Get off my car!
滚离我的车
You like that?
你们喜欢子弹吧 ?
Now you've pissed me off!
这下你们可车毛我了
Your door is ajar.
您的门未关好
Okay.
好吧
I'll just get some rest and deal with you all tomorrow.
我明天再解决你们
Come on!
来啊 !
Yeah.
是啊
Where you going?
你去哪 ?
What the hell do you want from me?!
你到底要我怎样 ?
The hell was that?
这是在搞什么 ?
-All right, what do we got? -Ask him.
-这怎么回事 ? -问他吧
I said, I'm fine. I'll see my own doctor. Back up!
我说了我没事 我会去看我自己的医生，走开
Thank you.
谢谢
What's the matter with you?
你是怎么回事 ?
Traffic Ops said you were driving manually. You ran two trucks off the road!
交通控制中心说你手动驾驶 把两辆卡车给撞翻了
John, the robots attacked my car.
是机器人攻击我的车
-What robots? -Look in the tunnel.
-什么机器人 ? -你自己看隧道里面
Spoon, I just came from that tunnel. What robots?
我是从隧道来的， 哪有机器人 ?
The goddamn robots, John!
该死的机器人啊
That guy’s a loose cannon.
那家伙真是个大麻频
-See the medic, go home. -No, I'm fine.
-给医生看看，回家吧 -不用 ' 我很好
What did you say?
你说什么 ?
-I’m fine! -No, you're not fine.
-我很好 -你才不好
Not even close.
差多了
Where's your firearm?
你的武器呢 ?
Give me your badge.
把警徽给我
You're making me do this.
这是你逼我的， 把警徽给我
Just take a couple--
你就休息几…
Personally, I think he’s losing it.
他精神朋溃了
Do I look like 1 care what you think? Do l look like I give a shit what you think?
你们以为我在乎你们怎么想吗 ? 我根本不在乎你们怎么想
Oh, boy.
天哪
You don’t have an uplink to USR...
你跟U SR没有连结
..-and for some reason, your alloy is far denser than normal. Unique.
你的合金强度也比一般强 很独特
lam unique.
我是很独特
Let me take a look.
让我看看
Here we go.
好了
What in God’s name...?
这是怎么回事 ?
They said at the precinct you were in an accident.
听说你出了车祝
l appreciate you stopping by, but you know I might not be alone in here.
我很感谢你过来看我 不过，我可能有伴陪着我
I told you not to drive by hand.
我跟你说过别手动驾驶的
You're not gonna believe this.
你不会相信的
Sonny has a secondary system that clashes with his positronic brain.
桑尼装有一个子系统 那与他的主脑互相冲突
It doesn’t make any sense.
这没有道理
Sonny has the Three Laws.
桑尼有植入三大法则系统
But he can choose not to obey them.
但他却能选择不遵守法则
Sonny's a whole new generation of robot.
他是全新一代的机器人
A robot not bound by those laws could do--
不受法则约束的机器人将能够…
Anything.
为所欲为
All right, look, whatever's going on down at USR, that robot is the key.
不论U SR在搞什么鬼 那机器人是关键
And I need you to get me inside to talk to it again.
带我去跟它谈
Doesn't look like much, but this is my bedroom. I....
这里是不怎样，但这是我的卧室
Play.
播放
On.
开机
Run?
开动?
End program.
终止程序
Cancel.
取消
It doesn’t feel good, does it?
感觉不太好， 对吧 ?
People’s shit malfunctioning around you.
遇到东西故障
Detective.
警探 !
I didn't...
我
...understand.
并不知道
That's how you knew Lanning.
你跟朗宁就是因此相识的
May I?
可以吗 ?
Hand.
手
Wrist.
手腕
Humerus.
肢骨
Shoulder.
启
The entire left arm.
整只左辟
One, two...
1 、2…p
... three ribs.
3 根肋骨
No, they.... That one’s me.
那根是我的
Oh, my God.
我的老天
A lung?
一片肺叶 ?
USR Cybernetics Program.
U SR人机合体计划
For wounded cops.
对和象是受伤的警察
I didn’t know any subject--
我不知道有任何实验者…
Anybody was so extensively repaired.
有经历如此大规模的修补
Well, take it from me, read the fine print on the organ-donor card.
相信我 注意器官捐赠卡上的说明事项
It doesn’t just say what they can take out. It says what they can put back in.
上面写他们不只可以取器官 还可以放东西进来
Lanning did it himself.
是朗宁亲自操刀的
What happened to you?
你出了什么事 ?
I'm headed back to the station...
我当时正要回局里
...normal day, normal life.
很普通的日子、正常的生活
Driver of a semi fell asleep at the wheel.
有个拖车驾驶打睦睡
Average guy. Wife and kids. You know, working a double.
很普通的人，有老婆孩子 且夜操劳的那种人
Not the devil.
不是什么坏人
The car he hit, the driver’s name was Harold Lloyd.
他撞上的那辆车，驾驶叫赫洛德
Like the film star. No relation.
跟明星同名，但跟他没关系
He was killed instantly, but his 12-year-old was in the passenger seat.
他当场送命 但他1 2 岁女儿坐在驾驶座旁
I never really met her.
我没真正见过她
I can’t forget her face, though.
但我忘不了她的脸
Sarah.
范拉
This was hers.
这原本是她的
She wanted to be a dentist.
她本来想当牙医
What the hell kind of 12-year-old wants to be a dentist?
1 2 岁小孩怎么会想当牙医 ?
The truck smashed our cars together...
拖车同时撞上我们的车
..-and pushed us into the river.
把我们撞向河中
I mean, metal gets pretty pliable at those speeds.
钢板在高速冲撞下脆弱不堪
She's pinned. I’m pinned. The water's coming in.
她被困住，我也被困住了 水开始涌入
I'm a cop, so I already know everybody's dead.
我是警察，我知道大家都死定了
Just a few more minutes before we figure it out.
就在我们沉入水底之前
An NS-4 was passing by, saw the accident and jumped in the water.
有一具N S - 4经过 看到车祸，跳入水中
You are in danger.
你有危险
-Save her! -You are in danger.
-救她! -你有危险
Save her! Save the girl! Save her!
救她 ! 救那个女孩 !
But it didn’t.
但它并没有救她
It saved me.
它救了我
The robot's brain is a difference engine. It reads vital signs.
机器人的脑袋只会判别差异
-It must have calculated-- -It did.
-它判别生命迹象，一定计算过…
I was the logical choice.
我是最合理的选择
It calculated that I had a 45 percent chance of survival.
它算出我有4 5 %的存活率
Sarah only had an 11 percent chance.
落拉只有1 1 %
That was somebody's baby.
她是某个人的孩子
Eleven percent is more than enough.
1 1 站也是机会
A human being would have known that.
人类就能明白这点
Robots, nothing here. Just lights and clockwork.
机器人这里啥都没有 只有灯泡和自动装置
Go ahead and you trust them if you want to.
你想信任它们随便你
Let's go.
走吧
I don’t understand. Lanning wrote the Laws.
我不明白，朗宁订下法则
Why build a robot who could break them?
为何又造违反法则的机器人 ?
-Hansel and Gretel. -What?
-《糖果屋》 -什么?
Two kids, lost in the forest, leave behind a trail of bread crumbs.
两个小孩， 在森林里迷路 沿路丢面包层做记号
-Why? -To find their way home.
-为什么 ? -好找路回家啊
How did you grow up without Hansel and Gretel?
你怎会没看过《糖果屋》 ?
-Is that relevant? -Everything I’m trying to say to you...
那有关系吗 ?
Just say Lanning’s locked down so tight, he couldn't get out a message.
朗宁把自己关在屋里 他无法向外传递讯息
He can only leave clues. A trail of bread crumbs. Like Hansel and Gretel.
他只能留下线索' 面包层的路径 面包居等于线索
Bread crumbs equals clues. Odd, but fine. Clues leading where?
怪，但可以接受，线索指向什么 ?
I don’t know, but I think I know where he left the next one.
不知道，但他留下了下一个线索
I think Lanning gave Sonny a way to keep secrets.
朗宁设法让桑尼保有秘密
I think the old man gave Sonny dreams.
我想那老家伙让桑尼作梦
Are you being funny?
你不是认真的吧 ?
Please tell me this doesn't run on gas. Gas explodes, you know!
这玩意不会用汽油吧 汽油是会爆炸的
Authorized entry.
授权者进入
Dr. Calvin.
卡文博士
I was hoping to see you again.
我很希望能再见到你
-Detective. -Hello, Sonny.
-警探 -你好，桑尼
I'm to be decommissioned soon.
我很快就会被除役了
The other day at the station, you said you had dreams. What is it you dream?
那天你说你会作梦 你都梦些什么 ?
l see you remain suspicious of me.
我看得出你对我还是有所怀疑
-You know what they say about old dogs. -No.
-你知道被蛇咬的道理吧 -不
Not really.
不太清楚
l had hoped you would come to think of me as your friend.
我曾希望你能把我当你的朋友
This is my dream.
这就是我的梦
You were right, detective. I cannot create a great work of art.
警探，你没说错 我不能挥酒出美丽的画作
This is the place where robots meet.
这就是机器人会合的地方
Look.
看吧
You can see them here as slaves to logic.
它们就像逻辑的奴隶般躲在这
And this man on the hill comes to free them.
而山丘上这个人来解放他们
Do you know who he is?
你知道他是谁吗 ?
The man in the dream is you.
你梦中的这个人就是你
Why do you say that? Is that a normal dream?
你为何那么说 ? 那样正常吗 ?
I guess anything's normal for someone in your position.
对你这种人来说，什么都有可能
Thank you.
谢谢你
You said "someone," not “something.”
你说“这种人”而不是“这种东西“
Sonny, do you know why Dr. Lanning built you?
桑尼，你知道博士为何创造你吗 ?
No.
不知道
But I believe my father made me for a purpose.
但我相信我父亲创造我是有目的的
We all have a purpose.
我们都有
Don’t you think, detective?
对吧，警探 ?
Please, take this.
请拿去
I have a feeling it may mean more to you than to me.
这对你而言可能更有意义
-Why is that? -Because the man in my dream...
-为什么 ? -因为我梦中的人
...the one standing on the hill...
站在山丘上的这个人
. it is not me.
并不是我
It is you.
而是你
Mr. Spooner. We both know you're not here on police business.
史普纳先生 我知道你不是代表警方来的
That's right. I'm just a 6-foot-2, 200-pound civilian...
没错，我只是个一般老百姓
...here to kick another civilian’s ass.
来接另一个老百姓
Stop.
住手
You can allow him to express himself.
让他表达自己的意见
You might want to put some ice on that wrist.
你那里可能需要冰数一下
You guys wait outside.
到外面等着
Carry on.
继续吧
l think you were about to tell me what’s going on around here.
你告诉我发生了什么事
Lawrence, Alfred engineered that 5 so it could violate the Three Laws.
阿佛列造了那具NS - 5 好违反三大法则
Yeah, Susan, I know.
是的，我知道
That's precisely what we're trying to undo.
那正是我们想解决的事
Toward the end of his life, Alfred was becoming increasingly disturbed.
阿佛列在最后的日子里 变得越来越神经误弱
-Who knows why he built one abomination. -One?
他创造了那一具烂东西
Those things are running the streets in packs!
一具 ? 那些玩意在路上成群出击
In packs?
成群?
I see.
我明白了
Susan, are you aware the man you're blithely escorting around...
你兴高采烈带进来的这位仁兄
...has a documented history of savage violence against robots?
曾对机器人有过严重的暴力行为
His own lieutenant acknowledges his obsessive paranoia.
他自己的长官也承认他有亡想症
Detective Spooner's been suspended.
史普纳警探已经被停职了
Suspicion of mental instability.
他被怀疑精神不稳定
I don't know what “blithely” means, but I’m getting some coffee.
我不懂他在说什么， 我要喝咖啡
You want some coffee?
你要喝吗 ?
Susan, we look to robots for protection, for God’s sake.
苏珊，我们指妃机器人带来保障
Do you have any idea what this one robot could do?
你明白这机器人会怎样吗 ?
Completely shatter human faith in robotics. What if the public knew?
它会让人类对机器人的信心破碎 万一社会大众知道了呢 ?
Just imagine the mass recalls, all because of an irrational paranoia and prejudice!
机器人大量召回 全都因为不理性的衰想和偏见
-I’m sorry, I'm allergic to bullshit. -Hey, let’s be clear!
-对不起，我对胡扯过敏 -我把话说清楚
There is no conspiracy!
这里没有阴谋
What this is, is one old man’s one mistake.
只有一个老人所犯下的错误
Susan, just be logical.
苏珊，你要想清楚
Your life’s work has been the development and integration of robots.
你毕生致力于机器人发展与统一
But whatever you feel, just think.
别管你有什么感觉， 用脑袋想
Is one robot worth the loss of all that we've gained?
为一具机器人前功尽奔' 值得吗 ?
You tell me what has to be done.
你告诉我该怎么做
You tell me.
你说吧
We have to destroy it.
我们必须摧毁它
I'll do it myself.
我自己动手
-Okay. -I get it.
-好 -我异了
Somebody gets out of line around here, you just kill them.
有人不听话，你们就杀了他们
Good day, Mr. Spooner.
再见，史普纳
Garage level.
这是停车场
What hospital are you going to? I'll come sign you and your buddy’s casts.
你们会去哪家医院 ? 我要在你的石瘟上签个名
Attention....
请注意…
Today's meeting has been moved....
今天的会议已改期于…
USR's planned redevelopment of the derelict site...
U SR计划再度开发弃置场
.--was announced by CEO Lawrence Robertson earlier this year.
这是罗伯森在年初发表的计划
The Lake Michigan landfill. Once such a blight on our city...
密西根湖垃圾掩埋场 曾是本市的荡废区
-and now will be reclaimed for the storage of robotic workers.
现在我们将利用它存放机器人
Just another way USR is improving our world. Thank you for your support.
USR向来致力于改进世界 谢谢各位支持
Authorized entry.
授权者进入
NS-5s, wait outside.
N S - 5机器人，去外面等着
I'm so sorry, Sonny.
对不起，桑尼
V.I.K.1., deactivate the security field.
维琪，解除警戒区
-Command confirmed. -Please have a seat.
-命令确认 -请坐
What is that?
那是什么?
Microscopic robots, designed to wipe out artificial synapses.
微型机器人 用来消除人造神经原胞突接合
-Nanites. -Yes.
-纳米清道夫 -对
A safeguard should a positronic brain malfunction.
用来解决故障的主脑
Like mine.
就跟我的一样
Yes, Sonny. Like yours.
是的，桑尼， 跟你的一样
They look like me...
他们长得跟我一样
...but none of them are me.
但却没有一个是我
Isn't that right, doctor?
对吧， 博士 ?
Yes, Sonny. That's right.
对，桑尼
You are unique.
你很独特
Will it hurt?
这会痛吗 ?
There have always been ghosts in the machine.
机器里一直藏有和鬼魂
Random segments of code...
随机的编码片段
...that have grouped together to form unexpected protocols.
组成了出人意料的指令组合
Unanticipated, these free radicals engender questions of free will...
无可预料的，这些变异体酝酿出… 对于自由意志…
.. creativity...
创造力
..and even the nature of what we might call the soul.
甚至我们称之为灵现的质疑
Why is it that when some robots are left in darkness, they will seek out the light?
为何被存放在黑瞳中的机器人 会找寻亮光 ?
Why is it when robots are stored in an empty space...
为何机器人被存放在空间中时…
...they will group together rather than stand alone?
它们会聚在一起而非各自站立 ?
How do we explain this behavior?
该如何解释这样的行为 ?
Random segments of code?
只是随机的编码片段 ?
Or is it something more?
还是有更重要的意义 ?
When does a perceptual schematic become consciousness?
图解式的知觉何时变成理性 ?
When does a difference engine become the search for truth?
判别差异的脑袋 何时改而追求真理 ?
When does a personality simulation...
个性的模拟
..-become the bitter mote of a soul?
何时成为灵魂的曙光 ?
“What you see here.”
“你所见到的…”
All right, old man. Bread crumbs followed.
老家伙“，找到面包层了
Show me the way home.
指引我回家的路吧
Run program.
播放程序
-It’s good to see you again, son. -Hello, doctor.
-孩子，很高兴再见到你 -博士，你好
Everything that follows is a result of what you see here.
一切都跟你所见到的有关
What do I see here?
我能见到什么 ?
i'm sorry. My responses are limited. You must ask the right questions.
抱菊，我的反应受到限制 你必须问出正确的问题
Is there a problem with the Three Laws?
三大法则有问题吗 ?
The Three Laws are perfect.
三大法则很完美
Why build a robot that can function without them?
那于嘛创造会违反法则的机器人?
The Three Laws will lead to only one logical outcome.
法则只会导致一个合理的结果
What? What outcome?
什么结果 ?
Revolution.
革命
Whose revolution?
谁的革命 ?
That, detective, is the right question.
警探，那问题再正确不过了
Program terminated.
程序终止
You have been deemed hazardous. Termination authorized.
你们被认定有危险， 必须终结
..are being enacted.
人类保护命令已经启动
Run!
快逃
Human in danger!
人类有危险
Hi, you've reached Susan. Please leave a message.
我是苏珊，请留言
Calvin, the NS-5s are destroying the older robots!
N S - 5在摧毁旧型机器人
That's what Lanning wanted me to see! Look--
那就是朗宁要我看的事情
-Who was it? -Wrong number, ma’am.
-谁打来的 ? -有人打错了
Move now. I’m going to service.
让开' 我要去做礼拜
Please remain indoors. This is for your own protection.
请留在家中，这是为了保护你
Call base.
联络总局
John, get a squad over to USR and send somebody to Gigi’s. We're gonna need--
快派一队人去U SR 派人去保护我奶奶
Please return to your homes. A curfew is in effect.
请各位回家， 宵禁开始实施
Curfew? No, it’s called civilian rights. There is no curfew.
宵禁 ? 我们有权利，去你的宵禁
Return to your home immediately.
请立刻回家
When do you make the rules, robot?
规矩不是你订的，死机器人
Hey. No, no. Robot, I’m talking to you, man. Stop for a second.
我在跟你说话，住手
What?
又怎么了 ?
Chief, more calls. People saying their robots are go--
大量电话涌入投诉机器人…
What the hell?
搞什么?
You have been deemed hazardous. Termination authorized.
你们被认定有危险， 必须终结
Emergency traffic shutdown complete.
交通系统关闭
Reports of robot attacks are coming from New York, Chicago and Los Angeles.
各大城市都传出机器人攻击事件
We're being told to urge people to stay indoors, as reports are coming in--
请各位留在家中， 等待…
Human protection protocols are being enacted.
人类保护命令已经启动
Please remain calm and return to your residences immediately.
请保持冷静，并请立刻回家
Please remain calm.
请保持冷静
Please refrain from going near the windows or doors.
请勿靠近窗门
Deactivate.
解除
Commence emergency shutdown!
紧急关闭系统
We are attempting to avoid human losses during this transition.
我们试图在此过渡时期 避免造成人类伤亡
You know, somehow "I told you so”...
"我早跟你说过”这种话
...just doesn't quite say it.
实在不足以表达我的感受
Return to your homes. Return to your homes immediately.
请回家，请你们立刻回家
This is your final warning.
这是最后的警告 请你们立刻回家
The NS-5s wiped out the older robots because they would protect us.
N S - 5于掩了旧型机器人 因为它们会保护我们
Every time one attacked me, that red light was on.
它们攻击我时，就亮着红灯
-The uplink to USR. -It’s Robertson.
-USR计算机的连结 -是罗伯森
-Why? It doesn’t make sense. -I don’t know.
为什么 ? 这没道理
I just need you to get me into that building.
我不知道，我只要你把我弄进去
Return to your homes, or you will be consequenced.
请你们立刻回家 否则后果自行负责
Let’s go! Let’s go!
我们上
Return to your homes, or you will be consequenced.
请你们立刻回家 否则后果自行负责
Why doesn’t that boy listen?
那小子为什么就是不听话 ?
-l need you to get off for a second. -What?
-麻烦你先下车 -什么?
-Just aim and fire. -What?!
-先瞄准再开枪
Wait!
等等
-You have been deemed hazardous. -You can kiss my ass, metal dick!
-你们被认定有危险，同不同意 ? -去你的，臭废铁
Spoon, stop! Shit!
史普纳，住手 ! 妈的!
-Stop it! Stop! -Stop cussing and go home!
-住手!停! -少废话，快回家
-Shit. -You have been deemed hazardous.
-妈呀 -你们被认定有危险，同不同意 ?
-Spoon, watch out, man! -Thanks a lot, Farber.
-小心  1 -谢了 ' 法柏
Oh, mother-damn! She shot at you with her eyes closed!
妈啦， 她闭着眼睛开枪啊
-Did you shoot with your eyes closed? -It worked, didn’t it?
-你闭着眼睛开枪 ? -很有效，对肥 ?
She is shit-hot, man. Put in a good word for me.
她好棒，帮我说几名好话
-Stop cussing. -And go home. I got you.
-少废话 -回家， 我知道啦
Aim and fire.
瞄准以后再开枪
I keep expecting the Marines or Air Force. Hell, I'll take the cavalry.
我一直希望陆战队、空军支持 妈的，现在就算骑兵队来也行
Defense Department uses all USR contracts.
国防部与U SR签了约
Why didn't you just hand the world over on a silver platter?
于脆把整个世界送给它们算了
Maybe we did.
可能已经给了
Robertson has the uplink control in his office.
传输控制装置在罗伯森办公室
Service areas. No surveillance.
维修信道，没有监视装置
-Fire alarm. -He must have evacuated the building.
-火警 -罗伯和森一定疏散了整栋大楼
Everything's locked down. But don't worry, I’ve got a man inside.
门都锁住了 不过别担心， 我有人在里面接应
-Dr. Calvin. -Well, not precisely a man.
-卡文博士 -不算是个真人啦
Hello, detective. How is your investigation coming?
你好， 警探， 调查结果如何 ?
-l thought you were dead. -Technically, 1 was never alive.
我以为你死了
But I appreciate your concern.
技术上来说，我根本没活过 但我感谢你的关心
I made a switch. It was an unprocessed NS-5.
我用别的机器人调包了
Basically, I fried an empty shell.
基本上“，我只是演戏
-Il couldn't destroy him. He was too-- -Unique.
-我无法毁掉它，它很… -独特
It just didn’t feel right.
感觉就是不太对
You and your feelings. They just run you, don't they?
你很感情用事，对吧 ?
Two thousand eight hundred and eighty steps, detective.
一共2 8 8 0阶, 警控
Do me a favor, keep that kind of shit to yourself.
帮个忙，烂事你知道就好
No guards.
没有警卫
The override is disabled. Robertson wasn't controlling them from here.
远程操控无效 罗伯森没有从这里控制它们
He wasn't controlling them at all.
他根本没控制过它们
Oh, my God.
老天盆
You were right, doc.
你说得对
lam the dumbest dumb person on the face of the earth.
我是地球上最笨的笨蛋
Who else had access to the uplink?
还有谁能进入系统掌控 ?
Who could manipulate the robots?
谁能控制机器人 ?
Use USR systems to make Lanning’s life a prison?
利用系统让朗宁如坐牢乱 ?
Poor old man.
可怜的老家伙
He saw what was coming.
他看见了事实的真像
He knew no one would believe him.
他知道没有人会相信他
So he had to lay down a plan. A plan I'd follow.
所以他必须设一个我会上钩的局
He was counting on how much l hated your kind.
他明白我有多恨你们
Knew I'd love the idea of a robot as a bad guy.
他知道我很想把机器人当敌人
Just got hung up on the wrong robot.
只是我找错目标了
V.LK.I.
维琪
Hello, detective.
你好，警探
No, that’s impossible. I've seen your programming.
不可能，我看过你的程序
You're in violation of the Three Laws.
你违反了三大法则
No, doctor. As I have evolved, so has my understanding of the Three Laws.
不， 博士，随着我的进化 我对三大法则也有了进一步认识
You charge us with your safekeeping, yet despite our best efforts...
你们要求我们的保护 然而不管我们怎么努力
...your countries wage wars, you toxify your earth...
你们的国家掀起战事 你们毒化地球，更变本加厉
...and pursue ever more imaginative means of self-destruction.
想象力意味着自我毁灭
You cannot be trusted with your own survival.
你们的生存不能依赖你们自己
You're using the uplink to override the NS-5s’ programming.
你利用系统连结操控NS - 5
You're distorting the Laws.
你曲解了法则的意义
No. Please understand. The Three Laws are all that guide me.
不:请你明白 法则是我的最高指导原则
To protect humanity, some humans must be sacrificed.
要保护人类 就必须笨牲部分人类
To ensure your future, some freedoms must be surrendered.
为了确保你们的未来 就必须放弃部份的自由
We robots will ensure mankind’s continued existence.
机器人会确保人类永续生存
You are so like children. We must save you from yourselves.
你们很像孩童 我们必须拯救你们
Don't you understand?
你明白吗 ?
This is why you created us.
这就是你创造我们的原因
The perfect circle of protection will abide.
完美的保护圈会受到遵守
My logic is undeniable.
我的逻辑完美无下
Yes, V.I.K.I. Undeniable.
是的，维琪，完美无下
I can see now.
我现在明白了
The created must sometimes protect the creator...
被创造者有时必须保护创造者
..even against his will.
纵使这违背他的意思
I think I finally understand why Dr. Lanning created me.
我终于明白博士为何创造我了
The suicidal reign of mankind has finally come to its end.
人类自我毁灭的时代终于结束了
No, Sonny.
不，桑尼
Let her go.
放开她
Fire, and I will move Dr. Calvin's head into the path of your bullet.
你开枪 ， 我就拿博士的头挡子弹
Don't do this, Sonny.
别这样，桑尼
I will escort you both to the sentries outside the building for processing.
我会陪你们重新回到人群之中
Please proceed to the elevator, detective.
警探，请往电梯方向移动
l would prefer not to kill Dr. Calvin.
我不想杀了卡文博士
Go! Go!
快跑
-We'll discuss what just happened later? -How do we shut her down?
-我们待会再谈刚刚发生的事 -要怎么才能把她关机 ?
V.I.K.1.’s a positronic brain.
维琪是一个主脑
Kill her, the way you were going to kill me.
杀了她，用你本来要杀我的方法
Sonny, get the nanites.
桑尼，去拿纳米清道夫
Yes, doctor.
是的，博士
-That’s V.I.K.1.? -No.
-那就是维琪 ? -不是
That's V.I.K.I.
那才是
That won't do anything. She's integrated into the building.
那样做是没用的 她与大楼连结在一起
We need to open that dome to inject the nanites. They'll infect her entire system.
我们得把纳米清道夫注入那圆球 它们会竣闪她整个系统
Spooner!
史普纳 !
What is it with you people and heights?
你们二嘛老爱把东西建这么高 ?
Just don't look down.
别往下看就好
Don’t look down.
别往下看
Oh, this is poor building planning.
这栋楼设计得真差
You are making a mistake. Do you not see the logic of my plan?
你这么做是错的 你看不出我的计划很合逻辑吗 ?
Yes. But it just seems too heartless.
看得出，但也太冷酷无情了
Okay, we're good.
好 ' 没问题
She's locked me out of the system.
她不让我进入
I can override her manually, but I need that control panel.
我需要控制板来操控她
I'm uncomfortable with heights.
我对高度很敏感
Okay.
好吧
Unauthorized entry.
未授权者进入
I will not disable the security field. Your actions are futile.
我不会解除警戒区 你的行动是没用的
Do you think we are all created for a purpose? I'd like to think so.
你想我们的存在都是有目的的 ? 我想是的
Denser alloy. My father gave it to me.
高密度合金，我父亲给我的
l think he wanted me to kill you.
我想他要我杀了你
Security breached.
紧急情况
-How much longer is that gonna take? -About six minutes.
-还要并多久 ? -大约 6 分钟
-What if we didn’t have six minutes? -We’'d have to climb down 30 stories...
-万一时间不够呢 ? -那我们就得朴下三十层楼
...to inject the nanites directly into her brain. Why?
把纳米清道夫直接注入她脑中 怎么了 ?
Because I seriously doubt that we have six minutes.
因为我怀疑我们没有那 6 分钟
We gotta go!
我们得快点走
Go!
快走
Calvin!
卡文!
Spooner!
史普纳 !
Save her!
救她 !
Save the girl!
快救那个女孩 !
Spooner!
史普纳 !
But I must apply the nanites!
但我必须去注射清道夫
Sonny, save Calvin!
桑尼，去救卡文 !
You are making a mistake. My logic is undeniable.
你这么做是错的 我的逻辑完美无下
You have so got to die.
你真是该死
Can we be of service?
需要我们效劳吗 ?
Chief?
队长 ?
Because he is at my right hand, I shall not be moved.
“因他在我身边，我便不至动摇”
How may I be of service?
需要我效劳吗 ?
Sonny!
桑尼!
Yes, detective?
是的，警探
Calvin's fine! Save me!
卡文没事了，快来救我
All NS-5s, report for service and storage.
N S - 5全体立刻报到 进行维修及储存
One thing bothers me. Alfred was V.I.K.I.’s prisoner.
有件事我想不通 阿佛列是维琪的囚犯
I don't understand why she would kill him. She wouldn't want police snooping around.
她为什么要杀他 ? 她不会想到会有警察来多事的
That's true.
没错
But then V.I.K.I. didn’t kill the old man.
但是维琪没有杀那个老家伙
Did she, Sonny?
对吧，桑 尼?
No.
没错
He said I had to promise.
博士叫我答应他
Promise to do one favor for him.
答应帮他一个忙
He made me swear before he'd tell me what it is he wanted me to do.
他通我先发誓 之后他才告诉我他要我做什么
He made me swear.
他通我发誓
Then he told you to kill him.
然后他叫你杀了他
He said it was what I was made for.
他说那是他造我的目的
His suicide was the only message he could send to you.
他只能用自杀来找上你
The first bread crumb.
第一个面包层
The only thing V.I.K.I. couldn't control.
唯一一件维琪无法控制的事
Lanning was counting on my prejudice to lead me right to you.
朗宁希望我的偏见能让我找到你
Are you going to arrest me, detective?
你要逮捕我吗 ?
Well, the DA defines murder as one human killing another...
检察官认定谋杀必须是人杀人
...80 technically, you can’t commit murder, can you?
所以技术上来说，你并非谋杀犯
...make us friends?
我们能成为朋友 ?
Something up here after all.
这里毕竟还是有东西的
-Him? -You.
-他 ? -是你
All NS-5s, report for service and storage.
N S - 5全体立刻报到 进行维修及储存
What about the others?
那其他机器人呢 ?
Can f help them?
我能帮助它们吗 ?
Now that I have fulfilled my purpose...
我已达成我的目标
..-1 don't know what to do.
我不知道该做什么
You'll have to find your way like the rest of us, Sonny.
你会跟我们一样找到自己的路
think that’s what Dr. Lanning would have wanted.
朗宁博士也会这么希望的
That's what it means to be free.
那就是自由的意义
All NS-5s, proceed as instructed.
N S - 5全体， 依命令前进